oneopinion.com 2018-08-23

# OneOpinion - Privacy Policy

#### Modified: May 2018

#### Introduction

Critical Mix, Inc. ("Company," "we," "our," or "us"), owns and operates the website www.oneopinion.com (the "Site") as a data controller. We know that your privacy is important to you. Through the Site, we operate the OneOpinion service ("OneOpinion") through which we provide surveys that can be taken at the Site, on websites hosted by our clients, or via electronic notification methods such as, but not limited to, email. We provide statistical sample to organizations that conduct research primarily for marketing or for social science purposes. We're committed to helping you understand how we manage and protect the information we collect. We take privacy seriously and have taken many steps to help safeguard the information we collect from you.

Our Privacy Policy will tell you about

  *  **Introduction and Consent** – A description of the Policy, our legal basis for processing your personal information and what your consent means
  *  **Opt-In to OneOpinion** \- How you can join OneOpinion
  *  **The Information We Collect and Use** – A description of the information we collect about you and why we collect it.
  *  **Third-Party Data Suppliers** – How and when we collect information about you from third parties.
  *  **Third-Party Survey Opportunities** – How and when we offer you the ability to take a survey hosted by our clients.
  *  **Automated Decision Making** – How we use automated decision making.
  * **Data Protection** – How we protect the use of your personal information
  *  **Opting Out of OneOpinion** – How you can opt out of OneOpinion and manage your personal information.
  *  **Our use of Cookies** – How we use Cookies in our Site.
  *  **Information Sharing and Disclosure** – The limited circumstances under which we will share your personal information.
  *  **Communications from the Site** – How we will communicate with you.
  *  **Rights Pertaining to Electronic Notifications** – Your rights regarding electronic communications from us.
  *  **Security and Information Protection** – The technical security measures we employ to protect the security of your personal data.
  *  **Privacy Policy for Children** – How we treat Children’s’ data.
  *  **Changes to this Policy** – How we notify you of changes to this Policy.
  *  **Contacting Us** – How to get in touch with us and our Data Protection Officer.

Thank you for using OneOpinion.

#### Introduction and Consent

This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") is provided to inform you of our policies and practices regarding the information that we collect from you, including how we collect that information, the choices you can make about that information, how that information is used, and the circumstances in which we might share that information with third parties. By using or accessing the Site and participating in OneOpinion, you have agreed to the collection and use of your information by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy and agree to accept the terms of our Privacy Policy. Please take a moment to review the terms of our Privacy Policy and complete a consent form. Because your consent serves as our legal basis for processing your information, if you have not completed a consent form, please do not use the Site or participate in OneOpinion. If you revoke consent to any one of the ways we collect or process your information, we will no longer offer you the ability to participate in surveys at OneOpinion. Once you have revoked your consent, we will not collect any more information from you, but we will continue to process information about you we have already collected.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you may contact the OneOpinion Data Protection Officer, Jonathan A. Flatow at [privacy@oneopinion.com](mailto:privacy@oneopinion.com). If you have any Customer Service issues, please contact Customer Service here.

#### Opt-In to OneOpinion

Members may sign up for OneOpinion by completing the "double opt-in" process at our Site(s) or through the websites of one of our many clients, vendors, or entities with which we have a commercial relationship (our “partners”). During the double opt-in process, members are sent a confirmation email following an initial request to subscribe at one of our sites, including this Site, or one of our partners' Websites, and all members must affirmatively click an additional link in that confirmation email - confirming their opt-in preference.

#### The Information We Collect and Use

By information, we mean information about you collected through OneOpinion and our Site, including "personally identifiable information" such as your name, email address, residential or work address, certain demographic information, (like your age, gender, zip code, income) and profile data (like occupation, shopping habits, hobbies, interests, product ownership and other areas of interest) as certain surveys may be directed to those participants who meet a particular profile. Registration for OneOpinion is not required to view non-member areas of the Site. If you elect to register for OneOpinion, we ask you for information that enables us to provide you with access to and permit you to participate in OneOpinion. The information we collect will be used to determine whether you are eligible to participate in the survey and will also be maintained by us to enable us to provide you with more relevant surveys in the future. In addition, from time to time, we receive e-mail addresses from one of our partners, who may ask us to contact you to offer you a survey.

We may collect other information other than personally identifiable information, "anonymous information", such as your user name and password (your "Login"), IP address (which we typically do not use to identify you personally—see further discussion below under "IP Addresses"), and your website browsing patterns (discussed in further detail below). We use such anonymous information to serve you better and send you surveys that are most relevant to your interests. We and/or our data partners, where you have given such data partners your consent, may also seek other personally and anonymous information from you or where such information is otherwise publicly available.

We may also use GPS or similar geo-location technology to determine the city and/or geo-coordinates of where you are located, including when you are using a mobile device. As noted in the section on “Sharing” below, we may use and share your location information with our customers so that they can offer you survey opportunities based on your location.

In addition, our mobile applications may collect, among other things, certain information automatically, including, but not limited to the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device’s unique device identifier (UDID), the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browsers you use, and information about the way you use the mobile application.

#### Third Party Data Suppliers

From time to time we may use third party providers to validate the accuracy of personal information you provide, so that we may offer better statistical sample to our clients. We may use third parties, such as credit bureaus, publishers, ad-serving networks and public records, to provide us with data they have collected about you and append this data to your demographic profile. We gather this information to serve you better and send you surveys that are most relevant to your interests. In such cases only a minimum amount of information is transferred to these third parties to enable them to perform specific functions on our behalf. The collection and use of that data is governed by the privacy policy and legal terms of the terms of the data controller and the website using the data; it is not governed by Critical Mix.

#### Third Party Survey Opportunities

Additionally, in certain circumstances, we offer individuals the ability to participate in our clients' surveys outside of OneOpinion. If you are asked to participate in such a survey, we will request limited anonymous information about you. In some cases, after completion of the initial survey, we may request personally identifiable information about you in order to provide rewards, to offer you the opportunity to join OneOpinion, or to participate in further surveys.

You may be referred to OneOpinion or our surveys by one of our partners. In the event that we ask such partner to contact you with additional survey opportunities, we may share certain basic personal information that we understand such partner already maintains (such as your e-mail address and gender) as well as certain basic information regarding your OneOpinion activity (such as the last time you completed a survey).

Any information provided to us will be retained and used solely for the purposes of fulfilling your requests, responding to your questions, offering you opportunities to participate in surveys, performing and carrying out the terms of OneOpinion (including fulfilling any rewards), or communicating with you as a member of OneOpinion.

#### Automated Decision Making / Profiling

We use a combination of automated business rules and statistical algorithms to review your personal information in order to present you with surveys for which you are most likely to qualify.

#### Data Protection

We support the rights of our members by limiting the use of their information for legitimate market research purposes and we make every effort to conform to the efforts of the following organizations created to uphold ethical survey research

  * The Insights Association
  * Advertising Research Foundation (ARF)

Critical Mix is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). We also may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Critical Mix, Inc. complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Critical Mix has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Critical Mix commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Critical Mix at:

Critical Mix/OneOpinion  
Attn: Jonathan A. Flatow, Data Protection Officer  
53 Riverside Avenue Westport, CT 06880  
Phone: [1-888-511-4259](tel:18885114259)  

Critical Mix, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint.

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority in your country.

#### Privacy Shield Frameworks

Critical Mix complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. Critical Mix has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Critical Mix is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Critical Mix commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints first contact Critical Mix at:

Critical Mix/OneOpinion  
Attn: Jonathan A. Flatow, Data Protection Officer  
53 Riverside Avenue  
Westport, CT 06880  
Phone: [1-888-511-4259](tel:18885114259)  

Critical Mix has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>

#### Opt Out

Members can unsubscribe from OneOpinion at any time, no questions asked, and you can withdraw any previously supplied consent. We know that just because you joined OneOpinion a month ago doesn't mean that you necessarily want to stay on it forever. Every survey invitation we send is coded with a special footer that allows you to cancel your membership in OneOpinion automatically by clicking a link provided in the message. In addition, you can discontinue your OneOpinion membership by visiting the Member Section found at https://www.oneopinion.com/profile and following any instructions. You have the right to access, modify, restrict the processing of, object to the processing of, or have your personal information transmitted to another data controller, and to have your personal information deleted from our site. To exercise these rights, please visit the Member Section found at https://www.oneopinion.com/profile and follow any instructions. You may also exercise these rights by contacting our Data Protection Officer at the address or email listed in this Notice. We will respond to your request within 30 days. Upon unsubscribing from OneOpinion, or if you revoke any previously given consent, we will deactivate your membership account and you will not receive any further survey invitations; although you may continue to receive some previously prepared survey invitations for a few days following the termination of your membership. After unsubscribing or revoking your consent, we will retain your personal information for a period of [180 days]; however, we will continue to protect such personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy during that time. Please note we will not be able to delete data that has been technologically archived in our backup systems, but we can delete current live information in our database.

#### Aggregate Information

From time to time, we may collect general, non-personal, statistical information about the use of the Site and the Service, such as how many visitors visit a specific page on the Site, how long they stay on that page, and which hyperlinks, if any, they "click" on. We collect this information from you by "passive" means through the use of technologies such as "cookies" and IP addresses, which are discussed in greater detail below. We may also group this information into aggregate visitor data in order to describe the use of the Site and OneOpinion to our existing or potential business partners or other third parties, or in response to a government request. However, please be assured that this aggregate data will in no way personally identify you, other list members or any other visitors to the Site.

#### IP Address

An IP address is a number that's automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the web. Web servers, the computers that "serve" web pages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We collect IP addresses for purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to third parties and to track the use of the Site. When visitors request pages from the Site or click on a link in a mailing sent through OneOpinion our servers log the visitors' IP addresses. We reserve the right to use IP addresses to identify a visitor or member when it will enhance the user’s experience or if we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with the Site's policies or to protect the Company, the Sites, the Site's visitors, OneOpinion, our Internet Service Provider partners, the members or others.

#### Cookies

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for a number of purposes

**On Our Sites:** Most commonly, we use cookies to make web-surfing easier for you by saving your preferences while you're using our Sites. The use of cookies is an industry standard -you'll find them at most websites. We use cookies on the Sites to verify a member's login status. By showing how and when visitors use the Sites, cookies help us see which areas are popular and which are not. Information such as the total number of visitors to the Sites and pages viewed is most easily tracked with cookies. We may use the information from cookies to make improvements and updates to the Sites and to tailor our services to our visitors', members' and survey participants' needs.

a. Essential Cookies:

Imperium RelevantID| Essential Security Data  
---|---  
Imperva Incapsula| Essential Security Data  
OneOpinion| Essential Security Data  
  
b. Advertising

Alexa| Analytics/Measurement  
---|---  
Evidon| Analytics/Measurement  
  
c. Analytics and Customization

Amazon Web Services| Ad Serving, Ad Targeting, Analytics/Measurement, Content Customization, Optimization  
---|---  
CMIX ADVance| Online Ad Effectiveness/Exposure Tracking  
Google Analytics| Ad Targeting, Analytics/Measurement, Optimization  
InsightExpress| Analytics/Measurement  
Scorecard Research| Ad Serving, Ad Targeting, Analytics/Measurement, Content Customization, Optimization  
VoiceFive| Analytics/Measurement  
  
**For Banner Ads:** When you visit one of our Sites or take one of our surveys, without registering for OneOpinion, we may place cookies on your computer that alerts internet advertising networks that you have visited one of our Sites or surveys. These cookies, which do not track any personally identifiable information, allows us to ask internet advertising networks to serve you advertisements with respect to survey opportunities, OneOpinion and our Sites.

**For Brand Awareness Studies:** We may place cookies from a third party technology provider on your computer that signals when you visit a website that utilizes a supported internet advertising network. We provide only limited anonymous information to the third party technology provider, including certain demographic information and a coded user identification number. The signal emitted from the cookie includes solely the coded user identification number and the specific advertisement(s) that you may have viewed. Certain of our clients may ask us send you survey opportunities to determine the effectiveness of their internet advertising based on the signals sent by the cookie about the advertising you may have viewed. You may choose to opt-out of receiving these brand awareness cookies at any time by clicking on the following link: [http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/17264?v=1&nt=0&nw=true](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/17264?v=1&nt=0&nw=true). In the event you opt-out of receiving these cookies, we will no longer place brand awareness cookies on your system. As a registered member of OneOpinion, we will save this opt-out preference to your profile.By your use of the Sites and OneOpinion, you authorize cookies to be put in place and their use by us and our clients and business partners consistent with the disclosures above. The cookies will expire after one year.

You also always have the option of disabling the installation of new cookies and deleting existing cookies using your browser preferences. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent and to accept/reject such cookie(s) individually. However, please be aware that some features of the Sites will not function properly or may be slower if you refuse cookies.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons / Web Bugs):** Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly in HTML files and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We may use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications. We may also use them to confirm payment to our third party partners. If you no longer wish to receive our communications sent by email, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication.

#### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Except for the situations listed here in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your personally identifiable information with third parties.

**Survey Research Responses**  
Generally, we provide the results of survey research to our clients in aggregate form. Accordingly, except as expressly provided otherwise in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose to our clients your individual identity as a survey participant and/or your individual survey responses unless we obtain your permission to do so. Some of our surveys in which you might participate are part of larger research projects involving other research companies. With such “multi-tiered” projects, we may provide your individual identity as a participant and other information about you (including personally identifiable information) to other research companies, subject to their written agreement to keep that information confidential as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy.

**Agents and Third-Party Service Providers and Partners**  
We may sometimes use other businesses to perform certain specialized services such as data processing or other technology services. In such instances, we may provide your personally identifiable information to those businesses to the extent required for such processing or services, but they are not permitted to retain or use your information for any other purpose. Critical Mix’s accountability for personal data that it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Critical Mix remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Critical Mix proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

**Digital Fingerprinting**  
We may use digital fingerprinting technologies to assign a unique identifier or "Machine-ID" to a user's computer to identify and track the computer. OneOpinion works principally with a third party provider to deploy this technology (the "Technology") and does not use it to collect personally identifiable information, or track the online activities, of the user of a computer; and will not disrupt or interfere with the use or control of a computer or alter, modify or change the settings or functionality of a computer. We use the unique identifier to assist our clients in ensuring the integrity of survey results. The third party provider analyzes publicly available information and data obtained from the computer's web browser and from other publicly available data points, including without limitation the technical settings of the computer, the characteristics of the computer, and the computer's IP Address, to create a unique identifier assigned to the computer. The unique identifier is an alpha-numeric id. After creating the unique identifier, we do not retain the information analyzed by the Technology to create the unique identifier. Additionally, to assist our clients in protecting and ensuring the integrity of survey results, we (a) may link or associate your unique identifier to you and any of your personally identifiable information; (b) may share your unique identifier with our clients and with other sample or panel providers; and (c) may receive or obtain a unique identifier linked to you from a third party, including without limitation a sample or panel provider or a client of OneOpinion. Any unique identifier(s) received or obtained by OneOpinion and linked to a specific individual will be protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Change of Control / Asset Transfer**  
As the Company develops, we may buy other businesses or their assets or sell all or parts of our business assets. Customer information is generally one of the business assets involved in such transactions. Thus, in the event that the assets of the Company in whole or in parts are acquired by a third-party, customer information, including any visitor information collected through the Site or OneOpinion, would be one of the transferred assets. In the event of a corporate change in control or sale of all or parts of our business assets our users will be notified and given the opportunity to opt-out of any such transfer of their personally identifiable information to the new corporate entity or asset purchaser.

**Legal and Site Compliance**  
In certain situations, Critical Mix may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.  
The Company reserves the right to disclose member information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the Company's rights or property, other visitors, list members, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. The Company also reserves the right to disclose visitor or list member information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it. We may also use personally identifiable information to monitor compliance with the Site’s Terms and Conditions.

#### Communications from the Site

**Survey Electronic Notification**  
We will send you targeted and relevant surveys by electronic notification (such as, but not limited to, email, sms, social media, smart phones) as is necessary to fulfill OneOpinion to you.

**Service Notification**  
We will send you service-related announcements, which are not promotional in nature, on occasions when it is necessary to do so. For example, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we may send you electronic notification.

**Customer Service**  
Based upon the information you provide us, we will communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, to fulfill incentive requests, and to manage your account. We may communicate with you by electronic communication or telephone.

#### Rights Pertaining to Electronic Notifications

We regularly send electronic notifications to the members of OneOpinion. If you do not wish to receive them, you may opt-out and/or deactivate your account by following the instructions included in each communication.

#### Security and Information Protection

The security of your information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it; however, no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Firewalls**  
Protecting the security of your personal information is very important to us. When we store information that you have provided to us when registering for OneOpinion, that information is protected by security measures that include "firewalls" (a combination of computer hardware and software that helps keep unauthorized visitors from accessing information within our computer network), "intrusion detection systems" (a combination of computer hardware and software that helps detect any unauthorized visitors) and other tools such as data encryption and physical security, where appropriate. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or data repository can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while Company strives to protect your personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your personal information.

**Links to other sites**  
Please be aware that when you are on the Site, or when you receive an email message from us through OneOpinion, you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control. There may be links to other sites from the Site's pages or from the email message we send to you that take you outside our Site. These other sites may send their own cookies to visitors, collect data, or solicit personal information. The privacy policies of these other sites may be significantly different from this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites and cannot guarantee the security of any of your personal information collected there. Note that when you link to a third party site from the Site, you may see pre-populated data fields with your personal information; however, that information is not available to the third party unless you take certain actions on the third party's site, such as submitting a form.

#### Privacy Policy for Children

In the United States, and elsewhere where the law provides, we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 on the Site or through the Service without permission from a parent or legal guardian. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide any information to us. If we become aware that we have collected information from a child under the age of 13 without the permission of a parent or legal guardian, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

In countries that are subject to the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679, as may be amended from time to time (“GDPR”) we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 16 on the Site or through the Service without permission from a parent or legal guardian or a person holding parental authority over the child. If you are under the age of 16 and a citizen of a country subject to GDPR, please do not provide any information to us. If we become aware that we have collected information from a child under the age of 16 without the permission of a parent or legal guardian or a person holding parental authority over the child, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

#### Changes to this Policy

The terms of this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting a notice on the homepage of the Site for a reasonable period of time after such changes are made, that this Privacy Policy has been updated, and by changing the "Effective" date at the top of this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any changes.

#### Contacting Us

We value your opinions. If you have comments or questions about our Privacy Policy, please send them to the OneOpinion Data Protection Officer at [privacy@oneopinion.com](mailto:privacy@oneopinion.com), or contact:

Critical Mix/OneOpinion  
Attn: Jonathan A. Flatow, Data Protection Officer  
53 Riverside Avenue  
Westport, CT 06880  
Phone: [1-888-511-4259](tel:18885114259)
